GAURAV PANDEY

D-255, Nehru Colony, Dehradun 248001 • +91-956 022 5886 • jdevhimcs@gmail.com

Professional Summary

Self-motivated Sr. PHP Developer with a high level of experience working on multiple projects. Passionate and hardworking with penchant for meeting deadlines. Interested in roles with companies promoting best practices and offering diverse customer projects.

Skills

- Project Management
- Operations management
- Core PHP, Mysql, Python, Flask

- Team building
- Laravel, Codeigniter
- Drupal, CRM, E-commerce and CMS

Work History

Senior Software Engineer, 04/2020 to Current **SDS Transport** – Australia (Work From Home)

- Trained and supervised 5+ team members for an ongoing Job Booking project.
- Represented web team at meetings with executives and discussed project goals and milestones
- Designed and executed security measures such as AWS and encryption
- Allocating daily jobs and workloads.
- Daily programming with technical issues debugging and team-leading were major roles
- Daily interaction with clients via skype and email to accomplish work.

Senior Software Engineer, 06/2017 to 02/2020 Bamko India Pvt Ltd – Dehradun, Uttarakhand

- Trained and supervised 5+ team members for ongoing E commerce projects
- Represented web team at meetings with executives and discussed project goals and milestones
- Designed and executed security measures such as firewalls and encryption
- Allocating daily jobs and workloads. Training new team members
- Daily programming with technical issues debugging and team-leading were major roles
- Daily stand-up meetings to keep team synchronized with each other
- Ensuring that development standards, policies and procedures are adhered to
- Implemented Agile Methodology to deliver quality and on-time delivery by using ASANA tasks management tool
- Daily interaction with clients via skype and email to accomplish work
- Successfully delivered 100+ b2b stores and b2c stores
- Delivered many projects by using PHP7, SOLID Principles, Test Driven Development, MYSQL (RDS), MS-SQL (RDS), Laravel, Codeigniter, Jquery, Ajax, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, PWA (Progressive Web Apps), AWS, mongodb, Stripe, Authorize.net

Senior Software Engineer, 05/2012 to 05/2017

24x7 Internet Technologies – Noida, Uttar Pradesh

• Built outstanding and dynamic team of software engineers and developers which significantly boosted overall success of organization

- Trained and mentor junior developers and engineers, teaching skills in Core PHP and Laravel and working to improve overall team performance
- Tested troubleshooting methods, devised innovative solutions, and documented resolutions for inclusion in knowledge base for support team use
- Collaborated with cross-functional development team members to analyze potential system solutions based on evolving client requirements
- Tested all software prior to applications going live to alleviate bugs and troubleshoot issues

Sr. PHP Programmer, 02/2011 to 05/2012

Brother Softs India – New Delhi, Delhi

- Used programming capabilities in PHP, SQL and JavaScript and other libraries as needed
- Conducted unit testing to deliver optimal browser functionality
- Build highly available, secure and scalable PHP applications and API
- Technical issues and testing guidance to testers
- Build efficient, testable, and reusable PHP modules

Mid Level PHP Programmer, 07/2010 to 02/2011

Sonitek Consultancy Pvt Ltd – New Delhi, New Delhi, India

- Created site layout and user interface using HTML and CSS practices
- Designed, implemented and monitored web pages and sites for continuous improvement
- Configured, installed and tuned PHP based systems
- Responsible for Bug fixing with tester
- Worked closely with team members to deliver project requirements, develop solutions and meet deadlines

Junior Programmer, 06/2009 to 06/2010

ProsoftWebmedia – Agra, Uttar Pradesh

- Worked as Jr. Programmer in C#, responsible for developing ERP system for Manufacturing Company
- Providing support to clients/users
- Daily Bug fixing with tester
- Regularly reviewed project documentation and made all important changes to match updates to project scope

Education

Master of Computer Applications: Computer Science And Programming, 06/2009 Uttar Pradesh Technical University - Farah, Mathura, Uttar Pradesh

Bachelor of Science: Mathematics, 06/2006

C.S.J.M. University Kanpur - Kanpur, Uttar Pradesh

Intermediate: Mathematics, 06/2003

Board Of High School And Intermediate Education - Uttar Pradesh

Project Summary

Online Exam System, work as project lead

Team Size – 5

• Multiple Center

- Super Admin/ Admin management with logs with center id
- Manage Teacher with center id
- Manage Students with center id
- Manage Subjects
- Exam management
- Result/Attendance
- Reporting

Responsibilities:

- Overall management and coordination of the programmer of projects
- Developed web applications using PHP, MYsql, Jquery, and Ajax.
- Used excel for upload bulk data.
- Developed weblogic using PHP
- Managing, utilizing and motivating resources across projects

E-commerce Website, work as Team Lead

Team Size – 8

- Responsibilities:
- Create Full documentation
- Create all milestones.
- Create Report According to client requirement.
- Executing to achieving departmental goals
- Overall management and coordination of the programmer of projects
- Developed web applications using PHP, MYsql, Jquery, mongodb and Ajax

ERP System, work as project lead

Team Size – 8

- Multiple warehouse
- Super Admin/ Admin management with logs with warehouse id
- Manage warehouse user with ACL
- Manage Enquiry, Supplier, Customer, PO, Account, Inventory etc
- Manage User Role, Out Enquiry, Customer Quotation, Item management
- Hr Management, Invoicing, Employee management, Reporting, Sales Analysis
- Multi Currency management, Vendor management, Shipping, Order Fulfillment
- Reporting, Order Tracking, SRM, After Sales Support

Responsibilities:

- Overall management and coordination of the programmer of projects
- Developed web applications using PHP, MYsql, Jquery, Laravel, mongodb, AWS and Ajax.
- Used excel for upload bulk data.
- Developed weblogic using Laravel
- Managing, utilizing and motivating resources across projects

Personal Details

Father's Name: - Mr. Ashok Kumar Pandey

Date of Birth : - 30-09-1985 Marital Status : - Married

Religion : - Hindu

Nationality: - Indian

Known languages: - Hindi, English